IAN R. McCAUSLAND

imccausl@icloud.com

http://www.ianmccausland.xyz

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Graduate-level researcher and instructor whose research and teaching revolves around meaning-making and communication in popular culture advertising and television. I have eight years of experience as a marker-grader and tutorial leader, involving editing, proof-reading and instructing students on English grammar, style, tone, clarity and logical argumentation.

- Proficient in XML, HTML, CSS3 and jQuery.
- Interdisciplinary collaboration
- Written and spoken communication

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- 2015, Publication of Book Chapter: "'Stasis Interrupted': Subjectivity and Christianity in David Fincher's Alien³" in God and Popular Culture (Denver: Praeger).
- 2008-2010, Western Graduate Research Scholarship
- 2006, Government of Alberta Jason Laing Scholarship for Academic Achievement

WORK HISTORY

June 2014 - Present

Shift Supervisor (promoted from Barista April 2015), Starbucks Canada, Toronto, Ontario

Leading a team of 3 – 6 baristas in their daily activities to ensure organization, structure and efficient store operations by delegating tasks, coaching and recognizing achievements; controlling daily inventory to achieve daily sales targets and minimize waste; taking initiative to solve problems as they arise with customers, facilities and equipment; communicating daily objectives and promotions with baristas and reporting issues to manager.

September 2010 – April 2016

Tutorial Leader, York University, Toronto, Ontario

Synthesizing, summarizing and clarifying complex and disparate course materials around a central thematic objective; leading discussion with students on lecture and course readings; marking and editing major research papers, short assignments and written exams; communicating constructive feedback to help my students succeed. Tutorial leader for *Introduction to Traditional and Popular Culture* (2010-2016).

September 2008 – April 2010

Tutorial Leader, University of Western Ontario, London, Ontario

Synthesizing, summarizing and clarifying complex and disparate course materials around a central thematic objective; leading discussion with students on lecture and course readings; marking and editing major research papers, short assignments and written exams; communicating constructive feedback to help my students succeed. Tutorial leader for *Diasporic Film* (2008); *American Television* (2009), *Media in Society* (2009), *History of Communication* (2010).

EDUCATION Doctorate, Humanities

York University Toronto, Ontario

2010-2016. Withdrawn without completion.

Master of Arts, Theory and Criticism University of Western Ontario London, Ontario February 2011

Bachelor of Arts, English University of Calgary Calgary, Alberta June 2007